ALWIN WOO

alwinwoo@yahoo.com·+65 9877 3382 https://www.linkedin.com/in/alwinwoo https://www.credly.com/users/alwin-woo·https://alwinwoo.github.io

CAREER SUMMARY

Alwin Woo is an accomplished professional with a diverse background in cybersecurity, data analytics, corporate strategy, finance and organizational development. With over 20 years of experience in various industries, he has a proven track record of driving business transformation, leading complex projects, and building high-performing teams. He also has extensive experience in corporate KPIs/dashboard reporting, risk management and possesses a wide network and in-depth knowledge of the Singapore Public Service and statutory boards to help companies succeed.

SKILLSETS

- Strategic Planning
- Corporate KPIs / Dashboard Reporting
- Policy Writing

- Project Management
- Change Management
- Risk Management
- Finance Reporting and Budgeting
- Cybersecurity
- Data Analytics
- Mentoring
- Organisational Design and Development

WORKING EXPERIENCE

OCT 2023 TO PRESENT

FOUNDER, ELYON INFINITE PTE LTD

I leverage generative AI to empower individuals in overcoming challenges of self-expression on social media. This includes designing prompts that guide users through AI agents to facilitate confident communication, reducing the stress of articulation. This enhances social media presence, fosters inclusivity, and cultivates a diverse range of voices, contributing to a more enriched and inclusive digital landscape. My AI agent was awarded the NYP Jumpstart Grant in November 2023 for market validation and testing. We are currently in the ACE Jan 2024 Incubator Programme, aiming to secure VC seed funding.

NOV 2022 TO JAN 2024

CHIEF OF STAFF / SENIOR CONSULTANT, EVVO LABS PTE LTD

I align and prioritise efforts towards achieving company's regional expansion plans, facilitate collaboration opportunities with international partners and build relationships with stakeholders. Internally, I refine processes and provide leadership to ensure key projects and initiatives are effectively planned, executed and monitored. I am also part of Evvo's consultancy team providing CISO, DPO-aaS,

cybersecurity consulting and risk assessment services for Cyber TrustMark, MAS TRM compliance and ISO27001 certification to our customers.

FEB 2017 TO SEP 2022

ASSISTANT DIRECTOR (FINANCE) / (LEADERSHIP & ORGANISATIONAL DEVELOPMENT), MOH HOLDINGS PTE LTD

I oversaw the company's annual workplanning cycle - from collating submissions from business units to submission for budget approval by Board members. In 2021, I oversaw a business process review of our subsidiary's 1FSS call centre, review its business continuity plan and conducted the annual BCP exercise. My team in MOHH organized workplan seminars and townhalls to disseminate work plans to all staff, help to orientate staff through engagement programmes and inculcated core values to promote desired organizational culture. We also conducted organizational climate surveys to understand staff sentiment, one of which was a nation-wide survey to understand the working experience of junior doctors done in 2019.

JUN 2015 TO NOV 2016

ASSISTANT DIRECTOR (OFFICE OF STRATEGIC PLANNING), SINGAPORE MANAGEMENT UNIVERSITY

I oversaw the annual workplanning cycle and tracking of corporate KPIs. I also prepared policy research papers such as reviewing projected annual SMU cohort intakes for the President and assisted in the SMU's Quality Assurance Framework for Universities (QAFU) assessment exercise.

MAR 2008 TO JUN 2015

ASSISTANT DIRECTOR (STRATEGY AND BUSINESS TRANSFORMATION), HEALTH SCIENCES AUTHORITY

I oversaw the annual workplanning cycle and tracking of corporate KPIs. My team led the development of HSA's 5-year strategic plan, conducted retreats and management discussions, tracked and reported organizational KPIs, budget utilization, project initiatives and outcomes. I supervised the Mapping of Manpower Capability and Identification of Skills Gaps exercise, led the HSA Horizon Scanning team as part of a corporate BPR exercise and headed the internal communications effort as part of the H1N1 Crisis Core team. I was the HSA Board, EXCO and Corporate Services Secretariat for close to 5 years and helped to formulate and implement R&D ethics approval and funding.

APR 2006 TO FEB 2008

MANAGER (THE ENTERPRISE CHALLENGE, PS21 OFFICE), PRIME MINISTER'S OFFICE

I promoted the TEC innovation fund through roadshows, events and awards, identified and nurtured innovative ideas for funding, administer approved budgets and expenses, recommended rectification actions when required.

SEP 2004 TO MAR 2006

PRUDENTIAL ADVISER, PRUDENTIAL ASSURANCE COMPANY SINGAPORE

I sought out prospects, understand their financial needs and conducted analysis to recommend suitable products to achieve their desired life outcomes.

JAN 2000 TO AUG 2004

ACCOUNT MANAGER (ARMY AND AIRFORCE), DSO NATIONAL LABORATORIES

I supported workplanning efforts to engage Army and Airforce key appointment holders, help connect customers to specialists within the company and supported major events promoting defence and R&D such as Asian Aerospace, Army, Airforce and Navy Open Houses.

I was a key organizer responsible for the Defence Science Matters! Exhibition held at the Science Centre in 2003 and had overseen getting more than 80 exhibits ready for the exhibition.

EDUCATION

- **2023 SPECIALIST DIPLOMA IN BUSINESS AND BIG DATA ANALYTICS, NANYANG POLYTECHNIC**
 - **CERTIFIED IN CYBERSECURITY (CC),** (ISC)²
- 2020 FUNDAMENTALS OF THE PDPA ACT, NTUC LEARNING HUB
- **2012 PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL (PMP),** PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE, USA
- **2002 MASTER OF ENGINEERING SCIENCE (TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT),** UNIVERSITY OF NEW SOUTH WALES, AUSTRALIA
- **1999 BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (MECHANICAL) HONS, NANYANG TECHNOLOGICAL** UNIVERSITY, SINGAPORE
- **1995 GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN MARKETING,** CHARTERED INSTITUTE OF MARKETING, UK

ACTIVITIES

Mentoring, Programming, Writing, Reading, Swimming

COMPUTER SKILLS

Python, PHP, SQL, Linux, Tableau, SAS Viya, Tableau, KNIME, CSS, HTML, Swift